? Oh, you want a villain? Let me show you how I evil ?
? Oh, you think I'm difficult? I'll show you all my devil ?
? Sharpshooter, lethal 'Cause I'm a messy, feminine diesel ?
? Wow ?
? Paint the town blue Riots all around you ?
? Riot ?
(金克丝 皮尔特沃夫 通缉)
? Paint the town blue Riots all around you ?
? Crush, crush, crush Crush you all beneath me ?
? You bitches are my pups You're droolin' for a squeaky ?
? I skewer all you said Now the battlefield is greasy ?
? Dig my nails into your peach You know, 'cause we are not amici ?
? Paint the town blue Riots all around you ?
(蓝色)
(金克丝)
? Paint the town blue Riots all around you ?
? Riot ?
(金克丝 皮尔特沃夫 通缉)
? Paint the town blue Riots all around you ?
(蓝色狂潮)
? I wake up to the sounds Of the silence that allows ?
? For my mind to run around With my ear up to the ground ?
? I'm searching to behold The stories that are told ?
? When my back is to the world That was smiling when I turned ?
? Tell you you're the greatest ?
? But once you turn, they hate us ?
? Oh, the misery ?
? Everybody wants to be my enemy ?
? Oh, spare the sympathy ?
? Pray it away, I swear I'll never be a saint, no way ?
? My enemy ?
? Pray it away, I swear I'll never be a saint ?
? Look out for yourself ?
《英雄联盟:双城之战》
第二季第四集
本WEB版外挂字幕由  风吹来的那片云  双语合并
又醒了
Up again?
你多睡一会儿也不会怎么样
The city's not going anywhere.
我明天一早安排了去见石匠工会的人
I have an audience with the Masons' Guild first thing in the morning.
我猜又是来告诺克萨斯的状的
Let me guess. Complaints about the Noxians.
诺军要求我们修建的 防御工事又翻倍了
They doubled their fortification requests. Again.
- 说是... -“为了保护我们”
- To keep-- - Keep us safe.
我没想到这件事会持续这么久
I never expected this to go on so long.
我以为...
I thought...
我说不清楚
I don't know what I thought.
反正不是现在这样
Just... it wasn't this.
你可以直接叫停
You could call it off.
让他们从底城撤兵
Withdraw from the underground.
你可以重组议会
Reestablish the Council.
只要你一声令下就行
All you have to do is give the order.
那得先抓住金克丝
Not without Jinx.
而且撤了兵情况 也不见得会好转 毕竟...
Besides, a withdrawal could lead to a worse situation than the one--
还有安蓓萨
Okay, Ambessa.
她帮我们拿下了底城 她说到做到
She delivered us Zaun, as she vowed.
没有她 不知道还要赔上多少执法官的性命
Without her, who knows how many Enforcers we'd have lost?
我从她身上学到了不少
I've learned so much from her.
你才是我们的头
You're our leader.
全体执法官 皮城的所有人
The Enforcers, Piltover,
大家只追随你
they follow you.
我也只追随你
I follow you.
你先去睡吧
I'll come to bed soon.
好男 好女 好朋友们
Ladies and gentlemen,
这儿可不是你们该来的地儿
you're in the wrong place.
恶棍 无赖 街溜子们
Scumbags and scalawags,
把你们的狗爪子 铁爪子都拍起来
put your hooks and paws together
最无耻 最下作 最血腥的决斗马上开始
for the meanest, ugliest, goriest spectacle of your lives.
擂台这边的是我们的常胜将军
In the gray corner, our undefeated champion.
他的利爪所向披靡
With claws like daggers
一口尖牙更是锋利无比
and teeth like sharper daggers.
他是恶贯满盈 谁见谁怕的臭臭嘴
The devilish, the wretched Stink Maw!
在擂台另外一边的是挑战者
And in the other gray corner, the challenger.
他是角斗界的新秀
A rising star,
他青面獠牙
with hideous mandibles
那副模样连育母蜘蛛看了都无地自容
and a face that would make a brood mother squirm.
他就是丑中之王
The creepy,
尖牙利齿怪
the dastardly Scuttle Butt!
两兽即将登场
Two will enter.
究竟谁输谁赢 比过才知道
And after that, who knows?
驯兽人 放你们的猛兽出来吧
Handlers, release your beasts.
不 你这是怎么搞的
No, no. What are you doing?
倒是卖卖力气啊
Show some effort.
恭喜你 这把你赢了
Congratulations on your victory.
好吧 看来常胜将军也不常胜
Well, you're past your prime, champ.
那岂不是只能...
Only thing to do is--
再比上一场 来个东山再起
A rematch? Return of the titans.
复仇吧 救赎吧
Vengeance. Redemption.
赶紧再放点臭气吧
The inexplicable release
别再藏着掖着了
of bodily gases.
(金克丝)
好吧 好吧
All right, all right.
虽然我不认为这是什么好点子
I still think it's a dumb idea.
不过谁叫你赢了呢
But I guess you won,
只好愿赌服输了 就依你的
and a deal's a deal. I guess.
喜欢吗
You like it?
算你走运
You're lucky.
我老姐在我小时候 可从没给我搞过这些
I didn't get to do much of this with my older sis.
她成天想的都是打打杀杀
She was more into... hitting things.
那会儿我还不叫金克丝
I had a different name back then, you know.
那时候叫爆爆
Powder.
是不是挺傻的
Stupid, right?
还以为我早就把那傻大姐给忘了
I thought I was rid of her for good, but, uh...
可你又让我想起了她
you kind of remind me of her.
是塞薇卡教你这么干的
Did Sevika put you up to this?
我已经洗手不干了 小鬼
That's a past life, kid.
都是些陈芝麻烂谷子的事了
And it was about as sweet as last year's milk.
金克丝早就死了
Jinx is dead.
是谁说这皮城里 到处都是聪明绝顶的发明家
How, in a city teeming with brilliant inventors,
怎么我们费了半天劲找来的
have we managed to unearth such
全是这种不顶用的废物
unrelenting incompetence?
是他们在搞鬼
This is their doing.
还不确定是不是黑色玫瑰...
We can't be certain the Black--
不许再跟我提这个名字
Keep their name out of your mouth.
我们还不确定 令杰斯和黑默丁格失踪的幕后黑手
We can't be certain the Order was also behind the disappearance
是教团还是另有其人
of Jayce and Heimerdinger.
还能是谁
Who else?
这座城市一到我们手里 就变成了一潭死水
The moment we seize control of this backwater,
但凡有点本事的人全都没影了
everyone with an inkling of talent vanishes.
哪有这么巧的事
It's no coincidence.
我们的直觉是对的
Our instincts were right.
他们畏惧海克斯科技
They fear Hextech.
可惜晚了一步
But we were too slow.
怎么就没想到先摁住那帮科学家呢
How could I not secure the scientists?
我女儿在他们手上 雷克托斯
They have my daughter, Rictus.
有机会出手的
Our moment will come.
但您必须做好准备
But you must be prepared.
为了提高效率 加快进程
To expedite processing,
请将您的所有箱包提前打开 等待检查
have any and all bags open and ready for examination.
快走
快点 跟上
我们将尽一切努力保证 皮尔特沃夫的安全
Officers ask for your cooperation and compliance
同时我们的官员也希望您能够
as we make every attempt
配合我们的工作
to ensure the safety
- 服从安排 - 下一个 快点走
- and security of Piltover. - Next. Move along.
重复一遍 为了提高效率...
To expedite processing...
要恨就恨金克丝
You have Jinx to thank for this.
她不是你们的朋友
She is not your friend.
也不是你们的英雄
She is not your champion.
她躲起来 留你们在这儿受罪
She hides while you suffer.
就这样的人 你们还不把她交出来
And yet you refuse to hand her over.
服从安排
...the safety of all citizens...
各类枪支弹药严禁携带入内
快走
Let's go.
金克丝
Jinx.
你说对了
You're right.
像她的东西化成灰我都认得出来
It's hers. I'd recognize it anywhere.
可除了这个都不像她
That's where the similarities end.
没弄出人命 也没故弄玄虚
No body count. No theatrics.
是不是有人故意模仿她
You think it's a copycat?
像是被我们逼急了 在乱抓救命稻草
I think we've made them desperate for something to believe in.
这点骚动不影响我们早上说的那些话
This doesn't have to change what we talked about this morning.
- 你还是... - 诺伦执法官
- You can still-- - Officer Nolen.
最近来得还挺勤啊
Quite the familiar face these days.
将军
General.
我有事找吉拉曼恩指挥官谈
I'd like a word with Commander Kiramman.
单独谈
In private.
我想不需要我来提醒你
I suppose I don't need to advise you
公私不分会带来什么不良影响吧
on the hazards of professional entanglements.
我想你来找我 应该也不是为了这个吧
Nor is that the advice you rushed here to provide.
虽说得知了金克丝现身的消息
It's beyond question that the news of Jinx's return
底城人又会重燃反抗之心
will ignite Zaunite resistance.
可凡事有坏处 必有好处
But the blade cuts both ways.
她的行踪我们已有了线索
There's a trail. We have her scent.
我还以为这样的进展能激起你的斗志
I'd expected this development would encourage you.
你的手下雷克托斯挑起争端
Was it for my encouragement that your man Rictus
也是为了激起我的斗志吗
was instigating violence?
你信不过我
You don't trust me.
凡事有好处 必有坏处
"The blade cuts both ways."
真是年少无畏
Fearless child.
你很敢说呀
You never shy.
那你有什么高见吗
You have a recommendation?
大闹检查站的就算不是金克丝本人
If it wasn't Jinx at the checkpoint,
也是知道她下落的人
one of them knows where she is.
逮捕是需要正当理由的
Arrests require cause.
让这座城市恢复和平
What greater cause is there
还有比这更正当的理由吗
than returning peace to this city?
为什么总要打着 和平的旗号动用武力呢
Why is peace always the justification for violence?
我们已经失去了太多
We've lost so many.
面对愤怒 面对悲痛
The anger, the sorrow...
快要承受不住 精疲力尽了
It's tiring. Gods, I know it's tiring.
但是她一天不落网
But you will never rest knowing
我们就一刻不得安宁
that she's out there.
或许是我小瞧了你
Or maybe I underestimated you.
或许你身上有我不具备的东西
Maybe you have the strength I do not.
对过去释怀
To forgive
对未来充满信心
and trust in tomorrow.
如何抉择由您定夺 指挥官
The decision is yours, commander.
想当年 我办的宴会是城里数一数二的
I hosted the most lavish galas in the city.
能成为我的座上宾 可是人们身份的象征
It was a measure of status to be on my guest list.
那时我多风光
Toast of the town.
可是现在人们躲我就像躲瘟疫一样
Now people avert their gaze when I roll by.
我可从来没有躲过您
My gaze isn't averted.
得了吧
Oh, spare me.
谁不知道你那张嘴跟抹了蜜似的
I wouldn't have hired you
就会讨好客人
if you weren't versed
不然我也不会雇你了
in the art of indulging your clients' egos.
你也算是议会硕果仅存的 元老级成员了
Plus you're one of the few councilors left from the old batch, right?
米达尔达家的少主 一点儿音信也没有 不是吗
Never learned anything about the younger Medarda, did they?
她人都没影了 怎么还是大家关注的焦点
Even when she's not here, she's all anyone talks about.
我明白
I get it.
毕竟她是米达尔达家族最后的继承者
She's the last heir of the great Medardas.
可是福是祸 人各有命
But the writing's on the wall.
都失踪那么久了
When you're missing this long,
怕是回不来了
you're not coming back.
下周还是老时间
Same time next week?
就明天吧
Tomorrow.
药效已经越来越弱了
The effects have been diminishing.
最近一直听人提起 说裂沟有个治疗师
I keep hearing about this healer down in the fissures,
住在荒郊野外
way out on the fringes.
都说他有起死回生的本领
They say he makes miracles happen.
我见过一次 可以说算得上是奇迹了
I saw one. Like nothing I'd ever seen before.
去见见也无妨 对吗
Can't hurt to look, can it?
你也应该提前说一声
You could have warned me.
想得倒挺美 有什么可说的
Fat chance. About what?
你在检查站搞的那出
Your stunt at the checkpoint.
听不懂你在胡说八道什么
No idea what you're babbling about.
难道不是你吗
That wasn't you?
反正不管怎么样
Well, however it happened,
现在整个底城都传遍了 说你回来了
the whole undercity's buzzing, saying you're back.
- 所以我才想... - 劝你还是别想
- So I'm thinking-- - Not your strong suit.
说不定会有转机
Would make a world of difference
要是你能站出来 当这个带头的
if you showed up. You're a symbol.
我当带头的
Ha. You want a symbol?
希尔科他这一辈子 一直在努力让底城团结起来
Silco spent his whole life trying to rally the undercity together.
谁想到老天开了个玩笑
Stupid joke that it is,
把办成这事的机会给了你
you have the chance to pull it off.
我说过了 我对这事没什么兴趣
I told you, I'm not interested.
你知道希尔科为了保护你
Do you know how much he sacrificed
付出多大代价吗
to protect you?
他始终相信 你是个好苗子
He believed in your potential.
那他就不该死
Well, then he shouldn't have died!
我今晚召集了大家
We're having a rally tonight.
在范德尔的雕像那儿
Vander's statue.
野火帮的人
Firelights,
拥护你的人
your fans...
能叫上的我全都叫上了
Anyone I can bring to the table.
你想在这里当缩头乌龟也行
Stick your head in the dirt if you want,
不过别以为蹲在这儿就能自己骗自己
but this fantasy you've been living out here,
你也是时候该醒醒了
it's not gonna last forever.
出门别绊着自己
Don't trip on the way out.
这你都能受得了 小鬼
I don't know how you do it, kid.
我得去找个人烦烦了
I gotta go bother someone.
还是老样子 不理我 是吧
Still giving me the silent treatment, huh?
在你和伊莎面前
Between you and Isha,
我都不知道怎么耍贫嘴了
I'm losing my snappy comebacks.
我当英雄
Me, a hero.
这地方真的是要完蛋了
How screwed up is this place?
我知道塞薇卡说得对
I know Sevika's right,
而且或许这是我欠你的
and I probably owe it to you,
都是因为我闯下的那个大祸
on account of the murdering and all.
不过我现在有别的事情想做
But I got something going now.
我交到了朋友
A friend.
我想好好对她
And I don't want to mess it up.
就像你当年对我那样
Maybe that's what I was like for you.
你要是这么想让我帮忙
If you care so much about me
玩你那个改变世界的破游戏
playing your stupid revolution game,
就赶紧吭一声
speak up now,
不然我就...
or I guess...
我就当你真的不在了
I guess you... You're really gone.
那么我也没有理由再待在这里了
And there's no reason to stay here anymore.
雕像
Statue...
范德尔的雕像
Vander's statue...
大家以前确实有些恩怨
It's no secret we got history.
各帮各派都没少流血
Blood spilt on all sides.
可咱们在同一片土地上长大
But we grew up on the same streets.
吃过同一碗剩饭
Ate the same scraps.
不管你们怎么想
Like it or not,
我们现在都在同一条船上
we're in this mess together.
执法官抄了咱们的家
Enforcers raiding our homes.
诺克萨斯人把刀架在咱们的脖子上
Noxians down our throats.
许多人平白无故地被丢进大牢
Innocents getting carted off to Stillwater.
今天必须做个抉择
We gotta choose right now
大伙究竟是想认输
whether we're gonna throw in the towel
还是想团结一致 奋起反抗
or make a stand together.
不管你是野火帮的 站金克丝的
Not as Firelights or Jinxers
还是没了靠山的残兵
or washed-up goons.
- 你都是底城人 - 我们要见金克丝
- As Zaunites. - We wanna see Jinx!
- 我们要见金克丝 - 她在哪里
- Where is Jinx? - Where is she?
我们要见她
We wanna see Jinx!
金克丝在哪儿
- 快说 她在哪儿  - 她在哪儿
- Yeah, where is she? - Yeah, where's Jinx?
我们要见金克丝
原地抱头 原地站好
你们全都被捕了
You're all under arrest.
放下武器 放下
- Drop the blade. - Drop it.
放下你的武器
Drop the blade.
我回来啦
I'm back.
上次不算 今天咱们再比一次
Time to find out who's the new pebbleweight--
伊莎
Isha?
好吧 我懂了
Okay, I get it.
跟我玩捉迷藏是吧
We're playing that game, are we?
伊莎
Isha?
她被抓走了
They got her.
什么
What?
她去参加集会了
She came to the rally.
上城的人搞了个突袭
Topside raided the place.
所有人都被抓了
Took everyone.
金克丝 你知道你自己是谁
You know what you are.
够了 闭嘴 闭嘴
- Damn it, Powder! - Shut up. Shut up.
闭嘴
Shut up. Shut up.
别这么叫我 我现在叫金克丝
Stop calling me that.
- 她的名字叫金克丝 - 她是我妹妹
- Her name is Jinx. - She's my sister.
金克丝 你得去找到她
- Jinx. - You have to be someone else.
- 金克丝 - 别再藏了
- Jinx. - Jinx.
振作点 小家伙
Chin up, little one.
我跟你说个秘密
I'll tell you a secret.
我们不会待太久
We won't be staying long.
你这胳膊游不动泳吧
Don't suppose you can swim, huh,
左撇子
Lefty?
好吧 那就只能玩点花的了
Well, only leaves the fun option.
我已经开始后悔了
I'm gonna hate this, aren't I?
是我 你们在找的女魔头
It's me. Your vile villainess.
你们一闭眼就做上的噩梦
The author of your nightmares.
- 你们...能吓死你们的... - 你是谁
- The, uh, dread of your-- - Who are you?
金克丝
Mm, Jinx?
从来没听说过
Yeah, never heard that before.
你不打算把我抓起来吗
You're not gonna haul me in?
再邀功领赏 当大英雄去
Claim the prize? Be the big hero?
你瞎糊弄谁呢
You expect me to
你是金克丝
believe Jinx,
无恶不作的通缉犯
the master criminal,
就穿你这么条破裤子
wears pants like that?
我裤子招谁惹谁了
What's wrong with my pants?
裹着马戏团的破帐篷就上街了
You look like a half-eaten circus tent.
我就是金克丝
I am Jinx.
怎么就破帐篷了
"Half-eaten."
你能认真点吗
Can we focus?
赶快走
Let's go.
块头不小嘛
Whoo! Big mama.
你是怎么抓住她的
How'd you take her in?
我让她自己选是上这儿来
I gave her a choice between this
还是把她扔水里游会儿泳
and a swim in the harbor.
C区牢房 带走吧 执法官
Cell Block C. Carry on, officer.
是 长官
Yes, sir.
快走
Move it.
- 干什么呢 - 这儿还有孩子呢
Come on, man. I have a kid.
不能把我们困在这儿 放我们出去
You can't keep us in here.
大英雄 金克丝大人驾到
Here I am, your big fat hero.
你差点就错过了臭臭嘴的绝地反击
You're late for Stink Maw's great comeuppance.
那边什么情况
What the hell was that?
跟上
Move it.
都准备好
Stand down.
带她走
Get her out.
- 你还真是个... - 是个大英雄
- You really are a-- - Big fat hero.
被你逮到了 毛球
You got me, hairball.
不过你别得意
But just remember...
你可不是臭臭嘴
you're no Stink Maw.
笑一个
Smile.
爆爆
Powder?
字幕翻译: 付博文 韩一旻